<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers on Hongrui Cui&#39;s Homepage</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/paper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Papers on Hongrui Cui&#39;s Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Authenticated Garbling From Correlated OT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paper/cot_ag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paper/cot_ag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by [DILO22], we investigate what is the bare minimum we can
achieve using the correlated OT functionality in actively secure
two-party computation. We found that with the following two techniques&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;block COT and compression idea of [DILO22]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dual execution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can achieve constant (up to 5 bits per AND gate) overhead in terms of
one-way communication compared to semi-honest half-gate [ZRE15].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-way-communication&#34;&gt;One-way Communication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one-way communication result is published as &lt;em&gt;Actively Secure
Half-Gates with Minimum Overhead under Duplex Networks. In Advances in
Cryptology–EUROCRYPT 2023: 42nd Annual International Conference on the
Theory and Applications of Cryptographic Techniques, Lyon, France,
April 23–27, 2023, Proceedings, Part II (pp. 35-67). Cham: Springer
Nature Switzerland.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1007/978-3-031-30617-4_2.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LPN-based Signature from VOLE in the Head</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paper/resolved/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paper/resolved/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;VOLE in the Head&lt;/strong&gt; framework demonstrates very competetive
performance as compared to the traditional MPC in the Head
framework. This has been demonstrated in the &lt;strong&gt;FAEST&lt;/strong&gt; signature scheme
(Crypto 2023).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One natural ideal is to utilize this framework to prove other OWF,
e.g. LPN-based. In this work, we apply the sketching technique of
[BGI16] to prove that the LPN noise consists of a series of unit
vectors, and then apply QuickSilver to prove the validity of LPN
witness. After transforming the proof system under the VOLE in the
Head framework from designated verifier to public verifier, we get a
signature scheme called &lt;strong&gt;ReSolveD&lt;/strong&gt;. The scheme shows smaller signature
size as compared to previous state-of-the-art &lt;strong&gt;SDitH&lt;/strong&gt; (Eurocrypt 2023,
Asiacrypt 2023)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPC in Multi Heads</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paper/multi_heads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paper/multi_heads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper is about extending the classical [IKOS07] MPC in the Head
framework to prove statements that are shared among multiple provers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is somewhat dual to the distributed ZKP object. I gave a talk about
this &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/talk/flpcp/&#34;&gt;Crypto 2019 paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published as &lt;em&gt;A Multi-Prover Zero-Knowledge Proof
System.&lt;/em&gt; In European Symposium on Research in Computer Security
(pp. 332-351). Springer, Cham. &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1007%2F978-3-030-88428-4_17.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal One-time Signature</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paper/cs_wots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paper/cs_wots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hash-based signature is to be standardized by NIST. So
it is a natural question to study whether the currently being standarized
algorithm &lt;strong&gt;SPHINCS+&lt;/strong&gt; is indeed optimal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards this end, we discovered that the constant-sum encoding method
that appear previously in the literature, is encoding-size-optimal
among all tree-based one-time signature schemes. Moreover, by refuting
a DAG-based construction [BM96] our scheme appears to be the optimal
among all existing constructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is published as &lt;em&gt;Revisiting the Constant-Sum Winternitz
One-Time Signature with Applications to and XMSS. In: Handschuh, H.,
Lysyanskaya, A. (eds) Advances in Cryptology –
CRYPTO 2023. CRYPTO 2023. Lecture Notes in Computer Science,
vol 14085. Springer, Cham.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1007/978-3-031-38554-4_15.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple GCZK</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paper/simple_gczk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paper/simple_gczk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this paper we describe a simple GCZK protocol that works in the
reverse order compared to [JKO16]. Here the prover is the garbler and
the verifier use cut-and-choose to verify that the correct
verification circuit is garbled. In this way, the protocol can be made
public-coin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published as &lt;em&gt;A Simple Post-Quantum Non-interactive Zero-Knowledge
Proof from Garbled Circuits. In International Conference on
Information Security and Cryptology (pp. 269-280). Springer, Cham.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eprint.iacr.org/2021/1068.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
